### NANDHA KUMAR V (UI UX DESIGNER)

Coimabatore, Tamil Nadu.

+919952721508 | vnandhakumar93@gmail.com | https://www.behance.net/nandhakumar57

### **SUMMARY**

As a dedicated full-time designer for the past 4+ years, I have successfully completed numerous projects. I made business ideas that perfectly blend with the design. I love to simplify complexities, that's why I specialize in UI UX Designer, giving the best to the users that they can access conveniently and productively. With all my till date expertise, I'm ready to showcase my skills and contribute meaningfully to the growth of both myself and the organization in the days ahead.

#### SOFTWARE KNOWLEDGE

Figma

Photoshop

Illustrate

Canva

Adobe XD

Webflow

HTML5(Basic)

CSS(Basic)

## **TECH SKILLS**

- Analytics & Problem Solving, User Research, Wireframing & Prototyping, Usability Testing.
- Visual Design, Interaction Design, Design System, Using of AI tools & updating, User Interface.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**UI UX DESIGNER |** SPAN Technology Service Pvt Oct 2022 – Feb 2024

Coimbatore

- Collaborated on Tax Product like TruckLogics, Tax990, TaxBandits, and Wealthrabbit (Fintech), focusing on enhancing design consistency and usability for a positive user experience. Worked closely with stakeholders to define project requirements and translate them into intuitive design solutions.
- Established a comprehensive Design System in FIGMA & ServiceNow for various products, elevating design consistency and efficiency. Developed style guides and design systems to maintain consistency and streamline the design process.
- Led the creation of wireframes and Hi-Fi prototypes, resulting in improved user experience and a 35% reduction in development timelines.
- Provided mentorship and management to junior designers, ensuring excellence in branding and marketing design tasks. Conducted training sessions to educate on FIGMA tools and techniques.
- We had explored and worked on the RPA solution using UiPath.

**UI UX DESIGNER |** Swipewire Technologies

Oct 2021 - Oct 2022

Chennai

- Done Wireframe, prototypes, mockups, and visual designs using Figma and design tools for Gaming, Fintech and e-commerce websites.
- Analyzed competitors and conducted User Research to make a perfect design that best fits the requirements.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams including product managers and developers to ensure design feasibility and alignment with business goals.

**GRAPHIC DESIGNER** | Zewoke Business Solution Pvt Jul 2019 – Oct 2021

Coimbatore

- Designed graphics for print and digital media including logos, brochures, advertisements, and social media content.
- Worked closely with marketing and sales teams to develop creative concepts that effectively communicated brand messages and promotions.
- Conducted market research and trend analysis to stay informed about design trends and industry developments.
- Graphic designers create visual texts and imagery concepts, by hand or using computer software, to Communicate ideas that inspire, inform, or captivate consumers. They develop the overall layout and production Design for advertisements. E-publishing, Books, Magazines, Catalogs, Letterhead, Business Cards, Logos, website banner design, poster, App Screen design, etc.

### **EDUCATION**

**B.E** [Aeronautical Engineering]

60%

Nehru Institute of Engineering and Technology

2015